roost.com 2013-11-11

# Privacy Statement | VerticalResponse

**Effective Date: 05/01/2013**

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.verticalresponse.com](http://www.verticalresponse.com/).

### VerticalResponse has agreed to notify you of:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the web site
  2. The organization collecting the information
  3. How the information is used
  4. With whom the information may be shared
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under VerticalResponse's control
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact us by email at [privacy@verticalresponse.com](mailto:privacy@verticalresponse.com).

VerticalResponse has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/index.html) including transparency, aaccountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software or within our applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@verticalresponse.com](mailto:privacy@verticalresponse.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

VerticalResponse complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. VerticalResponse has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view VerticalResponse’s certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

### Information Collection and Use

VerticalResponse is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. VerticalResponse collects information from our users at several different points on our website. Information collected by VerticalResponse is relevant to internal customer management and facilitates activities such as creating new accounts, customer identification and billing.

### Information You Upload into VerticalResponse

VerticalResponse offers self-service direct marketing solutions for small and mid-size businesses. All client data uploaded into our system is stored in a personalized and secure location. VerticalResponse will not sell or rent any client data loaded into our system and only the registered account holder can gain access to the uploaded lists.

### Registration

No registration is required to view the VerticalResponse website. However, if you choose to register or provide personal information on our newsletter sign-up, free trial, order forms, affiliate, partner and job application pages or other areas of our site, we will ask for information which may include your name, email address, credit card information, company name, and phone number.

#### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

### Customer Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@verticalresponse.com](mailto:privacy@verticalresponse.com).

### Public Forums:

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [info@vertcalresponse.com](mailto:info@vertcalresponse.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

#### Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral/share service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. VerticalResponse does not store this information and uses this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

#### Surveys

From time-to-time, we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to monitor site traffic or personalize the site (in the case of anonymous information collected in surveys).

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our general website. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. We use session-based cookies that last up to 6 months to determine general effectiveness of marketing campaigns. In such cases, we increment an aggregate number indicating success for that marketing campaign, but do not tie it to any of your personally identifiable information. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our entire site.

We also set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. For these purposes some of our cookies may be tied to personally identifiable information such as your email address. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

#### Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our tracking utility company and service providers use both session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site and in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.

### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

#### Advertising

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (Link to TRUSTe global opt-out: [http://preferences.truste.com](http://preferences.truste.com/)/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

### Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with 3rd parties in the case they would like to know aggregate demographics of our audience. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We do not share personally identifiable information with 3rd parties who are not service providers.

We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and a web hosting company to manage our website on our behalf. We use Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order. When you sign up for our services service(s), we will share information such as your credit card information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties may not use your personally identifiable information for their own marketing purposes.

### Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we VerticalResponse are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by verticalresponse.com.

Our Web site also includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Security and Data Retention

This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

This security is enhanced by our use of firewalls protecting all of the VerticalResponse servers. We also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information.

When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at info!verticalresponse.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every month, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. If an employee were to violate VerticalResponse privacy practices, that employee would be subject to disciplinary action up to and including dismissal.

Finally, the physical servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure collocation facility, within locked cages that only VerticalResponse network administrators have access to. This facility provides security 24 hours a day, 365 days a year and guaranties our servers against power outages by using automated backup power systems.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [info@vertcalresponse.com](mailto:info@vertcalresponse.com). 

### Special Offers

We send all new members a verification email to verify password and username. Established members who have chosen to receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@verticalresponse.com](mailto:support@vertcalresponse.com).

### Administrative Type Email Communications

You will receive administrative emails such as an order confirmation that are related to the primary usage of our service. You may not opt-out of administrative emails. These administrative emails will not have any marketing, promotional or advertising material(s) in them.

### Correction/Updating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, delete, and update that user's personal data provided to us. This can be done by calling our toll-free telephone number at 1-866-6VERTICAL, by emailing our Customer Support at [support@verticalresponse.com](mailto:support@vertcalresponse.com), or by sending us a letter to VerticalResponse, attn: account updates, 50 Beale St, 10th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105. You may also go to your account and MyLounge Page on our website. If you would like your account deactivated or deleted please state this in your communications and we will do this. We will respond to access requests within 30 days.

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will prominently post those changes on our Homepage (located at [http://www.verticalresponse.com](http://www.verticalresponse.com/)) so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email prior to the change becoming effective. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

### Business Transitions

In the event VerticalResponse goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our website for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

### Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy we may need to disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our Web site.
